AYOBAMI **AJIBOLA**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Ini Bassey street Arab road Kubwa, Abuja, Nigeria · +234 8031957690

ayobamiajibola46@gmail.com · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

Dedicated and enthusiastic developer with four years of experience in web-based user interactions. I have extensive experience working with JavaScript, as well as its runtime environment and library (**Node.js and React.js**). My work is guided by the goal of creating solutions that use the best technologies to produce better user experiences using react and creating robust APIs with the RESTful concept.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2021 - TILL DATE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, A'MOBI LTD

My major responsibilities at A'Mobi includes; designing and developing Api's, build UI's and backend components for payment processing administration and management, define and document AWS best practices and strategies regarding application deployment and infrastructure maintenance

NOV 2019 – MARCH 2021

INTERN, A'MOBI LTD

Assisted developers in projects. Reviewed and tested new applications. Wrote documentations and design wireframe for web apps.

MARCH 2017 - OCT 2018

FRONT END DEVELOPER, TEETYTECH

Developed and implemented front end architecture to support user interface concept, worked closely with the UI/UX designer to transform designs into code.

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2015

B.LIS, UNIVERSITY OF MAIDUGURI, BORNO STATE, NIGERIA

Bachelor of Library and Information Science

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- NodeJS
- ReactJS

- PSQL
- MogoDB
- Sequelize
- AWS

- GIT
- REST API
- Redux
- Typescript

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2022

BACKEND DEVELOPER, PO2023-SMART-APP, ABUJA, NIGERIA

I am a member of the backend team working on the development of the PO2023-Smart-App. This solution aims to reduce election fraud in my home country Nigeria, by enabling party officials to report live election results in real time for transparency.

2019 - TILL DATE

FACILITATOR, SHE ICT SOCIETY (SIS), ABUJA, NIGERIA

I volunteer with SIS to teach and make computer education applicable, easy, and free for young girls aged 8 to 16 in rural Abuja, Nigeria, with a mentorship program integrated for their self-development and growth.